<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microsoft Word in Technical Writing on Writarium - Resources for Technical Writers</title>
    <link>https://writarium.github.io/msword/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microsoft Word in Technical Writing on Writarium - Resources for Technical Writers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://writarium.github.io/msword/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Covers, Titles, Logos, Copyright and Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://writarium.github.io/msword/working-with-cover-logo-title-toc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writarium.github.io/msword/working-with-cover-logo-title-toc/</guid>
      <description>Cover or Title Page All documents have a cover or a title page. It contains the logo, the title of the document, and the release or publication month and year. This is shown in the following figure.
Note: The cover or title page does not have a header or footer.
Working with Logos All documents must contain a logo wherever applicable. These logos are designed in different sizes and their usage depends on how and where they are used in the document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Page Elements</title>
      <link>https://writarium.github.io/msword/working-with-page-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writarium.github.io/msword/working-with-page-elements/</guid>
      <description>Inserting a Blank Page A blank page may be required after the Table of Contents to ensure that the first chapter starts on the odd page. This often depends on the length of the table of contents.
For example, if the table of contents is just one page in length, this makes a total of three pages before the text of the first page, which has the title page, copyright page, and Contents page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dividing Huge Word Documents into Small Chunks (Sub Documents)</title>
      <link>https://writarium.github.io/msword/dividing-huge-word-documents-into-small-chunks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writarium.github.io/msword/dividing-huge-word-documents-into-small-chunks/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Word Technical Support recommends that you avoid working with documents that are over approximately 100 pages. For all documents that are over 100 pages, you need to break them into separate Word files or subdocuments. Then you must use field codes to point to the separate documents, and compile a master table of contents and a master index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexes in Microsoft Word</title>
      <link>https://writarium.github.io/msword/indexes-in-word-documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://writarium.github.io/msword/indexes-in-word-documents/</guid>
      <description>Creating an Index Professional Indexers recommend using a variety of keywords and synonyms to create indexes. However, index entries are based on topic titles only. This is due to limited project times. Moreover, every released book has several ways in which readers can look up information of interest, including the tables of contents, keyword searches, and indexes. Few points to keep in mind while creating indexes are:
 Index entries should be in lower case, with the following exceptions:  Proper nouns Acronyms and abbreviations  Quotation marks appear before and after the words that you want to list in the index.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>